University of Waterloo

Co-operative Work Terms

Waleed Rizwan 20680917

3B Accounting and Financial Management, Honours, Co-operative Program Computing Minor

Work Term	Employer	Evaluation
Jan - Apr 2019	Office of the Auditor General of Ontario	SATISFACTORY
	Office of the Legislative Assembly	
	Toronto Ontario Canada	
	Auditor (Trainee Program)	
Sep - Dec 2019	Toronto Hydro Corporation	EXCELLENT
	Head Office	
	Toronto Ontario Canada	
	Senior Technical Student	
Sep - Dec 2020	Loblaw Companies Limited	EXCELLENT
·	Corporate	
	BRAMPTON Ontario Canada	
	Application Developer	

Planned Future Work Term(s)

Sep - Dec 2021

Dear Hiring Manager,

I am a fourth-year **Finance** student at the **University of Waterloo**. After reading your job posting I am sure that my combined skill set in **programming** and **finance** would help bring value to the team.

In my third year I made the decision to transition into Software Development after having fun working on some side projects. What I enjoy about **programming** is the process of planning, designing, and then gradually working on a project until I have a final product that does something interesting or makes a task easier.

Not long after my career transition, I was able to find an internship as a **Developer** at **Loblaws** in the Supply Chain sector, where I used the new low code tool **Appian** to deploy **websites**. Here I learned the fundamentals of **Agile** and **Scrum**, how to write **clean code**, how to properly **test code**, and how to **document** my work so other developers can understand.

To quickly summarize my **programming** abilities, I am a capable web developer utilizing the **React JavaScript** framework to build clean and responsive UIs. I can also manage backend tasks using tools like the **Python** web framework **Flask** to create an **API** to serve multiple functions. Some other frameworks/tools I have experience in using for web development are **Material UI**, **Redux**, **Bootstrap**, and **Firebase**. My **Python** skills are versatile beyond web development and can be applied to multiple areas. I have used them for purposes such as **option pricing** and **sentiment analysis** to analyze the emotions of Tweets.

All of my skills have come from project-based learning and not just reading or watching tutorials. Examples of my work can be found on my portfolio website **WaleedsCode.com** and my **GitHub** which is linked **here.**

Thank you for taking the time to review my application. I look forward to the opportunity of speaking with you to discuss my qualifications further and the nature of the position you have available.

Si	n	_	Δ	r	ام	l٠	,	
. วา	11		_		-	ı١	,	

Waleed Rizwan

Waleed Rizwan

w2rizwan@gmail.com | WaleedsCode.com | github.com/waleedrizwan

Skills

Languages: Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, Excel VBA, Bash

Tools: React, Redux, Node, Git, Flask, Netlify, Bootstrap, Material UI, AWS EC2, Firebase, Figma

Experience

Application Developer - Loblaw Companies Ltd.

September 2020 - December 2020

- Developed a new inventory control website using Appian to be used by all 27 distribution centers in Canada
- Reduced time spent on non-value adding tasks such as data retrieval and manual clerical work by 50%
- Improved user experience by implementing a French translation feature to translate the website content and store
 user's language preference in Oracle backend
- Resolved over 20 Jira tickets including bugs and upgrades, and confirmed with users
- · Led weekly meetings with warehouse managers to assist in migration from legacy software to new platform

Senior Technical Student - Toronto Hydro

September 2019 - December 2019

- Coordinated daily trade settlement with energy suppliers to verify expenses for finance team
- Used Excel VBA to calculate total charges per day using hourly electricity prices and actual usage data
- Preprocessed monthly invoices worth hundreds of millions of dollars to confirm accurate totals

Projects

Portfolio Partner

Portfolio Partner

- Built a free stock notification service for Canadian investors with 50+ registered users
- Saved users time through daily SMS notifications of portfolio performance updates
- Implemented an automated price watching feature to text users when stocks reach a given price
- Created a SPA using React, Redux, Bootstrap, Material UI, Firebase Auth and Realtime database
- Utilized the Yahoo Finance API to handle stock performance calculations and to monitor prices
- Wrote Python scripts to handle SMS notifications using the Twilio API, and a Linux instance deployed with EC2

Twitter Vibe Check
TwitterVibeCheck.com

- Created an open-source project to instantly summarize emotions of Tweets using sentiment analysis
- Developed a lightweight website using React, Redux, and Bootstrap
- Created a wrapper API using Flask to handle requests between users and the Twitter API
- Users have collectively analyzed **30,000+** Tweets to date

Open Check

devpost.com/software/opencheck

- Built a hassle-free identity verification and authentication platform for Hack the North 2021
- Designed and implemented a user dashboard using Figma and React

Investment Analysis Tool

github.com/waleedrizwan/portfolioanalysistool

- Implemented a Python Jupyter Notebook which lets users analyze a mock portfolio of stocks
- · Calculates historic and expected future return, market risk, and volatility of the portfolio
- Graph's all data over an 8-year period using Pyplot and Seaborn
- Uses the Yahoo Finance API to pull market data and performs calculations using pandas and NumPy

Education

University of Waterloo

September 2017 - Present

- Bachelor of Accounting & Financial Management, Co-op
- Deans Honors List (2017 Present)
- Minor in Computer Science (Functional Programming, OOP, Algorithmic Problem Solving)
- AFM 121 Teaching Assistant (Global Financial Markets Winter 2021)

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO UNOFFICIAL GRADE REPORT

Waleed Rizwan 20680917

3B Accounting and Financial Management, Honours, Co-operative Program Computing Minor

Spring 2021				
BET 10 CS 20 CS 23 ECON 23 AFM 43	24 00 00 31 31 33	Wealth Management Foundations of Entre Practice Concept for Adv Computer U Algorithmic Problem Solving Intro to International Econ Business Strategy		
Term Average: Fall 2020	N/A	Decision:		
	3	Co-operative Work Term		CR
	3	Communication		CR
Term Average:	N/A	Decision:		
Spring 2020				
AFM 32 AFM 34 AFM 37	11 22 44 77 16 80.4	Connections to Ethical Conte Derivative Securities Intro to Business Analytics Priv Equity and Venture Cap Intro to Computer Science 2 Decision:	ext Good standing	78 76 86 81 81
Winter 2020			· ·	
HRM 20 AFM 33	91 00 73 35 88.67	Intermed Financial Account 2 Basic Human Resources Mg Cases & Apps in Corp Finance Designing Functional Program Decision:	mt ce	CR 97 82 87
Fall 2019				
	2 5 N/A	Co-operative Work Term Project Management Decision:		CR CR
Spring 2019				
AFM 24 AFM 27 AFM 28	11 41 74 30 31 76.2	Connections to Bus Context Intro Business Information Managerial Finance 2 Intro to Org Behaviour Business Law Decision:	Good standing	75 81 74 75 76
Winter 2019				
	2 1 N/A	Reflection and Learning Co-operative Work Term Decision:		CR CR
Fall 2018				
AFM 20 AFM 27 AFM 29	1 02 04 73 91 09 73.25	Career Fundamentals Intro to Public Practice Intro to Applied Finance Managerial Finance 1 Intermed Financial Account 1 Intro to Academic Writing Decision:	Excellent standing	CR WD 80 60 74 79

١٨	/i	n	te	r	2	n	1	Q
	, ,				_	u	•	U

AFM	AFM 102		Intro to Managerial Acct	86
AFM	AFM 121		Intro to Global Financial Mkts	84
ECON	102		Intro to Macroeconomics	87
SPCOM	111		Leadership & Communication	87
STAT	211		Intro Stat & Sampling Acc	68
Term A	verage:	82.4	Decision: Excellent standing	
Fall 2017	•			
AFM	101		Intro to Financial Accounting	84
AFM	131		Intro to Business in N.A.	88
MATH	109		Mathematics for Accounting	91
CS	100		Intro Computing through Appl	90
ECON	101		Intro to Microeconomics	84
Term A	verage:	87.4	Decision: Excellent standing	

Waleed Rizwan 20680917

3B Accounting and Financial Management, Honours, Co-operative Program

This job is funded by the Government of Yes Canada's Student Work Placement Program. To be eligible you must be a Canadian citizen, permanent resident or a protected person defined by the Immigration and Refugee Protection Act. Do you meet this requirement?